Contact

kym@cupofteallc.com 5716853151 (Mobile) kym_ali@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kymali (LinkedIn) cupofteallc.com (Company)

Top Skills

Nursing
Healthcare Consulting
Informatics

Certifications

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Behavior Change Specialist Certified Mental Health First Aid Responder

Honors-Awards
Cerner Client Achievement

Kym Ali MSN, RN

Burnout Coach for Healthcare Professionals #### | Helping healthcare professionals successfully manage burnout | "You can't pour from an empty cup" ##

Vienna

Summary

We provide a supportive virtual space created by a healthcare professional for healthcare professionals who are sick and tired of being sick and tired.

Here you can exhale, relax, and unwind as you work with a Career Burnout Coach. I understand the stress and anxiety medical and mental healthcare workers face because I have also experienced compassion fatigue and burnout. Through behavior change techniques and self-care, We help our clients heal themselves and successfully manage stress from the workplace.

We will assist with helping you create an customized action plan to manage the physical and emotional rigger of our profession. We provide prevention and intervention coaching along with resources for compassion fatigue and burnout.

"You cannot pour from an empty cup" Let's connect today over a Cup of Tea. ##

Experience

Cup of Tea LLC CEO and Founder December 2019 - Present (9 months)

Cerner Middle East & Africa Clinical Strategist Consultant April 2019 - December 2019 (9 months)

- Cerner Client Achievement Recognition Decreased clinicians time in the chart and increased patient care time
- Facilitated high level client meetings with Executives and SME's
- Identified opportunities that will add value for the organization

- Ensured client is aligned with National Regulatory Guidelines and Evidenced Based Practice
- Ensured deliverables adhere to timelines
- Measured key performance indicators to validate ROI

Sidra Medicine

Assistant Nurse Manager/ Informatics Educator August 2014 - February 2019 (4 years 7 months) Doha, Qatar

- Activation of the countries first state of the art Women's Health Hospital
- Development of Nursing Policies, Procedures and Standards of Practice
- Supervised staff and responsible for Performance Development
- Cerner Workflow based Curriculum Development
- Informatics Education Department Strategic Plan Development
- Delivered classroom training for Cerner Power Chart Maternity, Ambulatory
 Organizer, Breast Milk Management and Care Compass.

New York Presbyterian Hospital Charge Nurse

September 2007 - April 2014 (6 years 8 months)

Greater New York City Area

Provided a full range of nursing care on a 27 bed unit. Services included assessments, OR prep, IV insertions and blood draws, medication administration, Foley insertion and maintenance, post-operative monitoring and education on self/infant care and breastfeeding support. Average patient load assignment was 5-6 couplets.

Education

Western Governers University

Masters in Business Administration, Healthcare Management (2018 - 2019)

Grand Canyon University

Master's Degree, Nursing Education · (2015 - 2016)

Florida International University

Bachelor of Applied Science (BASc), Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2003 - 2005)